They're selling postcards
of the hanging,
they're painting
the passports brown
The beauty parlor is
filled with sailors,
the circus is in town
Here comes the
blind commissioner,
they've got him in a trance
One hand is tied to
the tight-rope walker,
the other is in his pants
And the riot squad
they're restless,
they need somewhere to go
As Lady and I look out tonight,
from Desolation Row
Cinderella, she seems so easy,
"It takes one to know one, "
she smiles
And puts her hands in
her back pocket
Bette Davis style
And in comes Romeo,
he's moaning.
"You Belong to Me I Believe"
And someone says, "You're in
the wrong place, my friend,
you'd better leave"
And the only sound that's left
after the ambulances go
Is Cinderella sweeping up
on Desolation Row
Now the moon is almost hidden,
the stars are beginning to hide
The fortune telling lady
has even taken all
her things inside
All except for Cain and Abel
and the hunchback of Notre Dame
Everybody is making love
or else expecting rain
And the Good Samaritan,
he's dressing,
he's getting ready for the show
He's going to the
carnival tonight
on Desolation Row
Ophelia, she's 'neath the window
for her I feel so afraid
On her twenty-second birthday
she already is an old maid
To her, death is quite romantic
she wears an iron vest
Her profession's her religion,
her sin is her lifelessness
And though her eyes
are fixed upon
Noah's great rainbow
She spends her time peeking into
Desolation Row
Einstein, disguised
as Robin Hood
with his memories in a trunk
Passed this way an hour ago
with his friend, a jealous monk
Now he looked so
immaculately frightful
as he bummed a cigarette
And he when off
sniffing drainpipes
and reciting the alphabet
You would not think to
look at him,
but he was famous long ago
For playing the electric violin
on Desolation Row
Dr. Filth, he keeps his world
inside of a leather cup
But all his sexless patients,
they're trying to blow it up
Now his nurse,
some local loser,
she's in charge of
the cyanide hole
And she also keeps the
cards that read,
"Have Mercy on His Soul"
They all play on
the penny whistles,
you can hear them blow
If you lean your head
out far enough from
Desolation Row
Across the street
they've nailed the curtains,
they're getting ready
for the feast
The Phantom of the Opera
in a perfect image of a priest
They are spoon feeding Casanova
to get him to feel more assured
Then they'll kill him
with self-confidence
after poisoning him with words
And the Phantom's shouting
to skinny girls,
"Get outta here
if you don't know"
Casanova is just being
punished for going to
Desolation Row"
At midnight all the agents
and the superhuman crew
Come out and round up everyone
that knows more than they do
Then they bring them
to the factory
where the heart-attack machine
Is strapped across
their shoulders
and then the kerosene
Is brought down from the castles
by insurance men who go
Check to see that
nobody is escaping to
Desolation Row
Praise be to Nero's Neptune,
the Titanic sails at dawn
Everybody's shouting,
"Which side are you on?!"
And Ezra Pound and T.S. Eliot
fighting in the captain's tower
While calypso singers
laugh at them
and fishermen hold flowers
Between the windows of the sea
where lovely mermaids flow
And nobody has to think
too much about
Desolation Row
Yes, I received your
letter yesterday,
about the time the
doorknob broke
When you asked me
how I was doing,
was that some kind of joke
All these people
that you mention,
yes, I know them,
they're quite lame
I had to rearrange their faces
and give them all another name
Right now,
I can't read too good,
don't send me no more letters no
Not unless you mail them from
Desolation Row